Alexandre Garrefa

software developer

about

Sao Paulo Brazil

alexmrg@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/garrefa/ github.com/garrefa twitter.com/alexmrg

languages

portuguese native english fluent german notions

programming

Swift, ObjC JavaScript (ES5/6, node.js)

basic knowledge: Ruby, Python, Shell Script, C

interests

iOS Applications, backend, networking, application security, agile and XP, API design, design patterns, testable software, continuous deployment, continuous integration, modern languages, linux/unix systems, OSS, knowledge sharing, user experience, user interface

experience

Nov 15/Now Singu (www.singu.com.br)

CTO and iOS Developer

Singu is trying to be the Uber of beauty. Responsible to develop the iOS app and make sure everything else works. Review backend and payment logic. Take care of AWS infrastructure, supervision Android development. Managing a team of four other developers.

Nov 14/Nov 15 Concrete Solutions

iOS Tech Leader

Concrete is a big consultancy always full of projects. Banks, TV stations, ecommerces, and others. Designed and build the network and security layers of a bank framework which is used in all of they're iOS apps. Was responsible to help the other iOS programmers, evaluate new projects, interview candidates and facilitate the knowledge sharing so that everybody could learn and become a better programmer each day.

May 13/Nov 14MakeYou Inc, (www.make.me)

Senior iOS Developer

Main iOS developer, responsible for building, testing and deploying the app. Working remotely with a distributed team. MakeMe is a group challenge platform. It supports mobile group challenges to help coaches and trainers create and host challenge plans that engage and impact clients anywhere in the world. It helps promoting: health and wellness; personal or professional, learning and development goals; using mobile group challenges.

Jan 13/Apr 13 OnPlaces (www.onplaces.com)

iOS Developer

Developed the first version of they're social network app. With the app people can check the most interesting places to hangout and their Facebook friends in each of those places. Once there, they can check in and see who else is in the same place, send messages, post texts and comments about the place.

08/Jan 13 **Heurys Tecnologia LTDA (www.heurys.com.br)**

Mobile Office Director, iOS

Developer

Responsible for mobile projects, developing them when performed in iOS native platform and performing management when developed with GeneXus.

06/Dec 07

Agathos Tecnologia (www.agathos.com.br) Team Leader for voice infrastructure

solutions

Coordinator of the technical team of voice infrastructure solutions. Working with voice centers from Dígitro and Ericsson.

03/Jun 06

SPD Tecnologia (www.spd.com.br) From Internship to Network Security Analyst Network security analyst, expert in Linux operating systems. Configuration of firewall, proxy, DNS, load balancing, among others.

applications

2015-Now Singu (www.singu.com.br)

Customers and Professionals Apps

Responsible to work with the design team to prototype the apps and to develop it from start to finish. Implement push notifications, centralized navigation, screens layout, animations, network communication, error handling, analytics, crash report, tests, continuous delivery system.

2014-2015 Concrete Solutions (www.concretesolutions.com.br)

Many Apps

Itaú Bank network and security framework, Redecard payment app, super visioned some e-commerce projects like Dafiti, Netshoes, Centauro. Some Globo.com apps and frameworks. And others.

2012-2014 Meias Lupo (http://site.lupo.com.br/)

Enterprise: Sales Force System App +

Electronic Catalog

The project underwent production with the implementation of the SAP software in February 2013 and has been in operation ever since. Responsible for conducting survey of requirements with the customer, UX definitions, backend specifications for integration with the SAP software, the whole development of the iPad app, as well as being the link between the backend team and the SAP team. Participation in meetings with users, providing training and support during the operation. At the the time, the project was being used throughout Lupo's sales department, with around 130 representatives spread across the country, and, by January 2014, orders placed on the SAP reached more than 40,000.

2013 Restaurante Web App (http://www.restauranteweb.com.br/) Food Delivery

App by Just Eat

Consultancy and coach of the Dart Digital development team to adapt the app for Brazil.

2012 Meu Saara App - Apps Criativos (www.appscriativos.com)

Consultancy and development of the app. It is a guide to Saara, a shopping center in the city of Rio de Janeiro. The user can browse the stores by categories, check its location on the map, call the store, get directions to it and bookmark favorite stores.

2012 Pic2Party App - Apps Criativos (www.appscriativos.com)

App focused on sharing event photos. The host of the event can invite people to a shared photo album. Once invited to the group, all members have access to all photos. Development of the initial version of the app, iOS based UX consulting, backup system improvement and reduction of the size of the app.

2012 Mercado Ribeirão App

Consultancy focused on improving the performance of data loading and publishing the app in the App Store. Analysis of the loading routine code. By the end of the work, data loading time was reduced from 3 minutes to 10 seconds.

2012 TipsTap App

Consultancy on code quality and push notification deployment.

education

2007 **BS.** Computer Science

UNISEB Centro Universitário, Sao Paulo